Previously on "The Vampire Diaries"...
"吸血鬼日記"前情提要
- Silas.- Hello,my shadow self.
- Silas - 你好 我的影子
Every time I close my eyes,I can feel myself drowning,and I need to make it stop.
只要我一閉眼 就感覺自己在溺水 我要阻止這種感覺
- After months of heartache and pain... - Bonnie's dead,Elena.
- 在數月的身心俱疲後 - Bonnie死了 Elena
We still held on to hope.
我們仍懷希望
I want to use Silas' death to bring Bonnie back to life.
我想用Silas的死 復活Bonnie
I can feel you.
我能感覺到你
- Bonnie?- It worked!
- Bonnie? - 起作用了
I'm back.
我回來了
But our victories came at a cost.
但我們的勝利是有代價的
My hair is going gray,and my teeth are falling out.
我頭髮變灰 我牙齒脫落
I'm not sure what that suggests,but it's definitely not health.
我不清楚那預示著啥 反正不是健康的表現
You're aging,Katherine.You have a few months.
你在衰老 Katherine 你只剩幾個月了
Every supernatural being that passes over to the other side will pass through you.
每個超自然生物去那一邊時 都會穿過你
That's gonna hurt like a bitch.
那感覺劇痛無比
And new threats are about to arise.
新的威脅即將來臨
The good news about having vampire blood in your system is that's step one to creating a new vampire.
好消息是你身體裡有吸血鬼血液 也就是創造新型吸血鬼的第一步
This is step two.
這是第二步
Preliminary report subject 62547.
實驗對像 62547 初步報告
Subject has transformed from human to vampire in approximately 14 days.
實驗對像已從人類轉化為吸血鬼 用時大約14天
Indicators predict a positive response to first bag of undiluted Augustine blood.
跡象表明對首袋未稀釋Augustine血液 反映良好
Physical strength is an unforeseen side effect.
體力增強則是意料之外的副作用
Terminating transfusion.
終止輸血
Activating emergency procedures.
啟動應急程序
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=-Proudly Presents
-=伊甸園美劇 http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- -=伊甸園字幕站 http://ytet.org=- 榮譽出品 本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用於商業途徑
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com/bbs=-Sync: YTET-橙子
-=YTET-伊甸園字幕組=- 翻譯: Noodles 兜兜 絮兒 小蟲cherry 校對: 艾瑞瑞 時間軸: 橙子
The vampire diaries Season5Episode 8
吸血鬼日記 第五季 第8集
Hi,mom!
媽！
I know we haven't seen each other or talked in a while,so I wanted to make you a video update.
我知道我們有段時間沒見面或聊天了 所以我想給你上傳個視頻
Um,I finally finished my whirlwind summer tour,got a new do,
我終於結束了繁忙的夏季之旅 換了個髮型
and I'm in college at Whitmore,where grams taught.
並且我進了Whitmore學院 奶奶曾教書的地方
This is my dorm!It's huge,right?Look.It even has a fireplace!I mean,what dorm has a fireplace?
這是我宿舍 很大吧？ 看 有個壁爐 啥宿舍能有壁爐?
- Oh,here they are!Hey,guys!Say hi to my mom!- Hi!
她們來了! 姐妹們 跟我媽打招呼!
They're planning me a welcome party.Just... just something hokey.
她們正為我計劃歡迎派對 矯情得很
I miss you.Um,please come visit when...  When you get a chance.
我想你 有機會來看我
I'll,um,I'll talk to you soon.Bye.
再聯繫吧 拜
And by the way,mom,I'm not a witch anymore because I died and then came back from the other side.
順便說下 媽媽 我不再是女巫了 因為我死了又從那邊回來了
Yeah.I'm the supernatural anchor that connects our two worlds together,so...
對 我是連結兩邊世界的超自然錨 所以...
Technically,I'm a ghost that people can still see and touch,so...
準確來說 我是個鬼魂 人們能看見能摸到 所以...
OK.So I left out a detail... or two.
好吧 我遺漏了一個細節...或兩個
I'll explain when she visits.
等她來看我再解釋
- How big is this party going to be?- Well,let's see.
- 這派對要鬧多大？ - 我們來看
Silas and Tessa are gone,and you finally aren't.
Silas和Tessa都死了 但你最後回來了
Which equals massive cause for celebration!
這就相當於熱烈慶祝！
Which equals a massive party.
也就相當於大型派對
Hopefully since each of us have only made one friend in college so far.
但願吧 鑒於我倆到目前只各交了一個朋友
And given that mine went radio silent after he kissed me,
而且我那個吻了我之後就消失了
and your was last seen at a tea party for a vampire-hating secret society.
你那個最後一次見是在 仇視吸血鬼的秘密社團開得茶話會上
Augustine,right?
Augustine 對吧?
The one who covered up your roommate's death and wants to kick you off campus?
就是掩蓋你們室友之死 還想趕你們退學的人？
What?I've kept up!The other side is boring.What else am I supposed to do?
咋了? 我都知道啊! 那一邊很無聊的 不然我還能做啥?
All right.So Augustine wants us gone.Who cares?It doesn't matter.It's not gonna happen.
好吧 Augustine想趕走我們 誰在乎? 沒事的 我們不會走
We're moving on with our lives together as functional vampires,former witch anchor thing.
我們繼續生活 作為正常的吸血鬼 還有以前是女巫現在是錨的傢伙
I don't know.
我不清楚了
And we're having a party.
並且我們要辦派對
With jell-o shots!
喝著果凍酒!
Oh,shoot!Um,I have to go register for classes.
糟了! 我得去登記課程了
- What?- Nothing.
- 咋了? - 沒事兒
Have fun registering.
登記愉快啊
Oh,my God!Oh,my God!
天啊! 天啊!
Wait.Registering for classes?
等下 登記課程?
I know.I... she's... I know I have Elena's blessing.
我知道 她... Elena是祝福我們的
I still don't need to rub it in her face day one in the triple dorm room.
但我還用不著第一天就在三人宿舍惹眼
We could always sneak back to my place.
我們可以在我那裡辦事啊
You mean,Damon's house?
你說Damon家?
While we're at it,why don't we just have sex in his bathtub,or maybe Katherine could watch.
那說到這 我們不如在他的浴缸裡做愛 或者Katherine看著也行
This hair,by the way,kind of hot.
順便一說 這髮型挺性感的
- You ok?- Yep.
- 你還好吧? - 對
- I got to go to class.See you tonight?- Yeah.
- 我得去上課了 晚上見? - 嗯
Ok.
好的
I'm ready.
我準備好了
I know this is gonna sound lame,but...
我知道這聽起來挺遜 但...
Any time you start with this is gonna sound lame, guess what... it is.
每次你說這句話 肯定很遜
This is for Bonnie,and you had a really big part in bringing her back,so I think that you should come.
是為Bonnie 你為復活她幫了大忙 所以我想你該來
Oh!Wait.Hang on.Wait.
等下! 別掛
- Hey!Hey,Aaron.- Hi.
你好 Aaron
- Long time,no see.Here.You're coming.- Who's Aaron?
- 好久不見 喏 來吧 - Aaron是誰?
Party in a dorm.No,thanks.
宿舍派對 算了吧
I know what you're doing.
我明白你的心情
- You like to push people away,but the thing is... - How do you know that about me?
- 你不想讓人接觸 但事情是... - 你怎麼知道我是那樣?
Because you told me at the costume ball when I compelled it out of you.
因為在化裝舞會上我蠱惑你時 你告訴我的
Ok.Forget that I said that,forget that I know anything.We're starting over.
行了 忘了我剛說的話 忘了我所知道的事 我們重新來過
You're coming to my party.There will be free beer,and it will be really good for you.
你要來我們的派對 會有免費的啤酒 並且對你很有好處
- See you then.- See you tonight.
- 到時候見 - 晚上見
Well,that was an embarrassingly close call.
剛差點露餡兒啊
Maybe I should be there so you don't spill all of our secrets and make out with the moody mystery guy.
也許我該去 這樣你就不會把我們的秘密 都說出去並跟那個神秘憂鬱小伙親熱
The only moody mystery guy that I want to make out with is you.
唯一我想親熱的神秘憂鬱男子就是你
Oh,and speaking of which,invite Stefan.
對了 說到這點 把Stefan也叫上
Speaking of moody or making out?
你是說他憂鬱呢 還是他是你老相好?
Either way,he'll never show.His memory's back,and he remembers he hates us.
不管怎樣 他都不會去 他的記憶回來了 他會記得他恨我們
Just try,ok?I bought Bourbon,so he could just get drunk and hate us from afar.
試下好麼? 我帶了波旁酒 所以他喝醉了就不那麼恨了
Well,I'll be sure to relay the message.
我一定轉達消息
So apparently we've been invited to a college party.
顯然我們已被邀請去一個大學派對
Yeah.That was my first reaction,too.
對 我第一反應也是這樣
Then Elena promised a bottomless well of top-shelf alcohol.
然後Elena保證會有喝不完的上等好酒
Stefan?
Stefan?
You... ok?
你...沒事吧?
Yeah,I'm fine.
嗯 沒事
How about my favorite reading chair?
那我最愛的讀書椅呢?
Just tell Elena thanks,but I'm not really up for a party tonight.
告訴Elena我謝謝她 但我沒打算今晚參加派對
How about now?
現在呢?
Matty blue-blue,I want another drink.
陰鬱小Matty 我想再來一杯
No!You're drunk and scaring the customers.
不行! 你醉了 還嚇到了顧客
You realize that every single time you say no it just makes you hotter,right?
你要意識到每次你說不時 都會使你更性感 對吧?
What are you watching,some Czech reality show?
你在看什麼 某個捷克真人秀?
How'd you know it was Czech?
你怎麼知道是捷克的?
Eye contact.
眼神交流
We're getting started.
我們有戲
You translate,you drink.
想喝酒 就翻譯
Ok.What the hell am I looking at here?
我看到的這是啥?
So over the summer,I went to Prague,met a girl.She followed me back here.
夏天那會 我去了布拉格 遇見一女孩 她跟蹤我到這兒
And then her boyfriend put some spirit thing in my head.
然後她男友對我腦袋施加了什麼東西
- Oh,dear.This is bad.- Why?
- 親 這可不妙 - 為啥?
My friends will come looking for this blade.
我朋友會來找這把匕首
Protect it at all costs.
你要不惜一切代價保護它
Some guy named Kristof,he,um... He activated you.
是個叫Kristof的人 他...他激活了你
What do you mean activated me?
啥叫把我激活了?
He's a traveler.Travelers are a faction of witches.
他是個旅行者 旅行者是巫師的一個派系
They're big on spirit possession.You've got one inside of you.
他們喜歡佔取靈魂 你的就被佔取了
It's kind of like a human parasite that's hitching a ride in your brain.
就像一種人類寄生蟲 寄存在你腦袋裡
So how the hell do I get it out of me?
那我怎樣才能把他攆出我的身體
That girl,the one that followed you back from Prague,was she,
那個女孩 那個從布拉格 跟你到這兒的女孩
um,I don't know,feisty,a little accent,ridiculously beautiful?
恩 我不知道 是不是挺激進的 有點口音 很漂亮
Pretty much,yeah.Her name was Nadia.Why?Do you know her?
差不多 是的 她叫Nadia 怎麼了 你認識她
You could say that.
可以這麼說
I,uh handed out all the fliers.
我 額 我發完了所有傳單
Oh,and,uh,Damon said that he's gonna try and bring Stefan.
哦 還有Damon說 他會盡量把Stefan帶來
Funny.That seemed to imply that Damon is actually coming.
有意思 那好像暗示Damon真的會來
Maybe a call from a mysteriously hot biology T.A.will help.
也許來自神秘性感的生物學助教 的電話能幫到你
Well,look who rose from the dead.
哦 看看是誰起死回生啦
I need your help.
我需要你的幫助
What happened,Jesse?
怎麼了 Jesse?
Just come to my room,please.
趕快來我的寢室 求你了
Ok.I'm coming,but what's going on?
好的 我馬上去 發生什麼事了
It's a long story.My roommate's gonna be home.
說來話長 我的室友馬上回來了
Jesse!
Jesse!
Jess,you home?
Jess 你在家嗎
I'm sorry,man.
對不起了 哥們
Oh,my God.
哦 天哪
Who the hell turned you into a vampire?
哪個混蛋把你轉化成吸血鬼了
It was torture.
簡直是折磨
I was in some cell all day,and then at night,he'd take me out and do experiments on me.
我被關在一個小單間裡一天 然後晚上的時候他帶我出來做實驗
What kind of experiments?
什麼樣的實驗
I don't know.He'd starve me and then inject me with some weird blood.
我不知道 他先餓我一陣 然後給我注射一些奇怪的血液
What am I supposed to tell my parents?
我該怎麼和我爸媽說
They left me all these messages.They're wondering where the hell I am.
他們給我發了這麼多留言 他們想知道我到底在哪
We're going to call them and tell them that you lost your phone but you're ok.
我們會給他們打回去 然後說你手機丟了 但你很好
Where is Wes now?
Wes現在在哪兒
I locked him in his lab after I attacked him.
我咬了他後 就把他鎖在他的實驗室
Honestly,though,the escape was kind of a blur.I wasn't exactly in my right mind.
說實話 怎麼逃出來的我記不清了 我當時頭腦很混亂
Well,you're new,and you're hungry.
額 你剛轉化 而且你很餓
Not for long.I brought our stash.
不會餓太久 我把我們的存貨帶來了
How are you doing?
你怎麼樣
Our stash?You're a vampire,too?
我們的存貨 你們也是吸血鬼
You say it like it's a bad thing.
你這麼說好像多糟糕似的
First rule of being a vampire is realizing how awesome you are!
作為吸血鬼的第一條規矩就是 你要知道你有多酷
- How's he doing?- He's all right.He's alive.
- 他怎麼樣 - 他很好 他還活著
Elena,wait.I was thinking that Jesse could do it.
Elena 等一下 我覺得應該讓Jesse做
You're a vampire now.You may have hurt him,but you can also heal him with your blood.
你現在是吸血鬼了 你可以傷害他 但你也可以用你的血治癒他
Holy crap.That's insane.
我的天哪 這太不可思議了
You want to teach him about compulsion?
你想教他怎麼蠱惑人嗎
Hey,strange Lookie what I stole.
嘿 陌生人 看我偷了什麼
Knock yourself out.
您請自便吧
Hey.Come on.Please just have one drink with me.Please.
嘿 別這樣 求你和我喝一杯 求你了
Stefan,I've had a bad... Year really,and it would be nice to have a friendly face.
Stefan 我這一年過的都不好 你友善點 我就會好了
One pity drink.
可憐你一杯
See?The universe at work.
看 宿命發揮作用了
I don't know if you knew this,but our doppelganger stars are fated to be together,
我不知道你知不知道這個 但是我們二重身之星注定在一起
so like it or not,you're gonna end up with somebody who looks like me,
所以無論你喜不喜歡 你最終都要和長得想我的人在一起
although the universe seems to have all of its eggs in the Elena basket,
儘管 宿命好像孤注一擲在Elena身上了
but at this point,I don't really blame it.
但是在這件事上 我真沒什麼好怪它的
What is wrong with you?
你怎麼了
Other than the joint pain,receding gums,and the fact that I have to pee every 5 minutes,
除了關節痛 牙齦脫落之外 事實上我每五分鐘就要去次廁所
I'm dandy,but,hey,enough about me.Why are you all by your lonesome?
我可好著呢 但是 嘿 我說完了 你為什麼自己一個人?
So I could avoid talking to anyone.
這樣就可以不用和別人說話了
Well,if you did want to talk to someone,I'm right here,
額 如果你想說說話 我就在這兒
and,uh,let's be honest,I'm wasted,so I'm not gonna remember.
而且 說實話 我喝多了 所以不會記得
Look.I thought that killing Silas would allow me to move on with my life,but I was wrong.
聽著 我以為殺了Silas 就能夠繼續我的生活 但我錯了
I spent my summer locked in a safe.One minute,I think I'm fine,the next minute I feel like I'm dying all over again.
我一夏天都被鎖在保險箱裡 這一刻我很好 下一刻我好像又死了
Classic PTSD.
典型的創傷後應激障礙
You survived a pretty traumatic event,and now you're back,
你從創傷中活下來 現在回來了
and you've got nothing but free time to just relive that terrible experience in the safe.
你就是無事可做 只能想一想在保險箱裡不好的回憶
Well,allow me to give your life a purpose.
好吧 讓我給你點目標
Help me with one little favor.
幫我個小忙
Should have know this was gonna come around to you needing something from me.
我就知道在你身邊 不會有好事
I'm just trying to help.What would I know about posttraumatic stress?
我只是想幫忙 關於創傷後應激障礙 我知道什麼呢
I only had my newborn ripped from my arms by my judgmental father
我只知道我嚴厲的父親將我 剛出生的孩子從我懷抱裡奪走
and then had to run 500 years after my entire family had been slaughtered
然後逃了500年 在我全家被
by a psychopath,but,hey,that didn't have any lingering side effects.
一個精神病殺了以後 但是 嘿 沒留下任何副作用
Hey.All right.What do you need?
嘿 好吧 你想要幹什麼
I thought you never wanted to see me again.
我以為你再也不想看見我了
Why'd you call me?
為什麼給我打電話
Stefan,I'd like you to meet Nadia Petrova,my daughter.
Stefan 我很高興為你介紹我女兒 Nadia Petrova
- So your mom's like me,too?- Yeah.
- 所以你媽媽也喜歡我 - 是的
Long story.She's,um,surviving fine.You'll be great.
說來話長 她 額 依然健在 你會好好的
Your eyes keep scanning the room.
你的眼睛一直在掃視這間屋子
You afraid I'm gonna go vampire postal on the fourth floor freshmen?
你在害怕我會發狂 吸四樓新生的血嗎
No.I'm sorry.I'm just looking for my,um... I'm not sure what he is actually.
不是 抱歉 我只是在找我的 額 我不確定他到底是什麼
Boyfriend?
男朋友?
Friend with benefits?
床伴?
He's my best friend's little brother,he's still in High School,and I... Think I'm madly in love with him.
我好朋友的弟弟 還在念高中 我非常愛他
Have you been keeping an eye on Jesse?
你一直在監督Jesse?
Yep.I've been teaching him the art of sublimating vampire hunger via grain alcohol.
恩 我在教他如何把對血的渴望 轉移到酒上
And I sent Damon to question Wes.
我讓Damon去找Wes了
You realize that Damon's going to kill Wes,right?
你知道Damon會殺了Wes吧?
He's not going to kill him.He's getting information.
不會 他只是去問話
You realize that you're wrong,right?
你的判斷是錯的 明白嗎?
Ok.Look.I know that you're not crazy about Damon and I being together...
我知道你不喜歡我和Damon在一起
No,no,it's fine.I'm fine with you two being together
不 不是這個 只要你認清他這個人
as long as you can acknowledge the kind of person you are together with.
我對此毫無意見
What do you want?
你想幹什麼?
What I want is to be drinking copious quantities of booze and making out with my girlfriend,
想喝幾杯酒 跟女朋友親熱
but unfortunately,I can't do that until I get a bunch of answers out of you.
但前提是在你這找到一些答案
Careful with those.
小心
These?These right here?
小心什麼?這些東西?
Why?I mean,we're on a college campus,right,full of students?
為什麼?這不是在大學裡嗎? 這麼多學生啊
I can't imagine an M.D.has a bunch of infectious diseases just lying around.
一個醫學博士怎麼會把這麼多 病毒放在這裡
M.D.-PH.D.I'm a researcher.
我是MD/PHD雙學位 咱可是科研型的
Well,that explains it.I've met a lot of people like you.Science over medicine,right?
哦 難怪呢 見過很多跟你一樣的人 科研高於醫學對嘛?
Let me guess.You use these in your little vampire lab rats,don't you?
讓我看看 是用這些對吸血鬼做實驗吧?
Not in the mood to talk?Fair enough.
不想說話? 也沒事
We're gonna play a little game where I inject you with whatever the hell necrotizing fasciitis is.
玩個遊戲 給你注射 急性筋膜炎病毒
It's a flesh-eating bacteria.
是食肉性病毒
Gross.
噁心
So I'm gonna do that,and I'm gonna ask you a bunch of questions.
這樣吧 問你幾個問題
If you answer me correctly,I'm gonna give you some of my delicious...
如果答案正確 你會得到我可口的
Vampire blood,and we'll heal you right on up
吸血鬼血液 你會痊癒
If you don't answer me correctly,we're just gonna have to
如果回答錯誤 就等著看
see how much flesh these little guys can eat.
這些小東西的戰績吧
Just out of morbid curiosity,which one of you is younger?
有點好奇 你們誰年輕點?
- I am.- Right.
- 我 - 算了
Ok.So here's the knife the traveler left behind with me.Now what are we doing in here?
這是旅行者留下的匕首 要我來這幹什麼?
Take a seat,Matt.
Matt 坐
This is ridiculous.
無聊
Come forth.
出來
- What the hell was that?- She's calling on Matt's passenger.
- 這又是什麼? - 她在呼喚Matt的旅客
What am I doing here?
我怎麼在這裡?
It's okay, sweetheart.
親愛的 沒事
Easy,easy,easy.
冷靜 冷靜
Hello,Gregor.I'm Nadia's mother.It's a pleasure to finally meet you.
嗨 Gregor 我是Nadia的母親 很高興見到你
What do you want?
你想幹什麼?
Here's the thing.
是這樣
Nadia's my only child,so naturally,I'm suspicious of anyone who wants to date her.
Nadia是我唯一的孩子 所以 對她的戀人好奇也在情理之中
Why don't you tell us the real reason why you're in Mystic Falls?
為什麼不說出你來神秘瀑布鎮的 真實原因?
To track and kill Silas.
為了追殺Silas
Oh.So it has absolutely nothing to do with this?
噢 你不想要這個?
How did you get that?
你是怎麼得到的?
I would much rather be getting drunk right now,
我現在很想喝酒買醉
so why don't you stop wasting our time and tell us what you're doing here?
別浪費時間了 快說你在這幹什麼?
Fine.After Silas was dead,I was meant to kill her.
Silas死後 我本想殺了她
I didn't see that one coming.
這我倒沒想到
You were using me to get to her?Why?Why would you kill her?
你利用我接近她?為什麼? 為什麼要殺她?
That's what the travelers want.I don't question my orders.
這是旅行者的意思 我不懷疑我的任務
See why I don't want you dating my daughter?
知道為什麼我不喜歡 你跟我女兒在一起嗎?
Because travelers are ruthless,manipulative hypocrites.
因為旅行者們無情操縱狂一樣的偽君子
I know because your grandfather was one.
我之所以知道 是因為你的祖父就是其中之一
What did you just do?
你做什麼呢?
Give it a rest.Matt will be fine.Gregor on the other hand,not so much.
得了吧 Matt沒事 Gregor就說不准了
I just expelled his spirits.There's a reason why he wanted this knife so badly.
我剛驅走了他的靈魂 這是他為什麼想要這匕首的原因
It's the only thing that will truly kill a passenger.
只有這樣才能殺死旅客
Turning a kid into a vampire so you can experiment on him?Harsh.
為了實驗把個孩子變成吸血鬼? 真殘忍
What is it about this place that turns people into mad scientists?
這裡就是製造無良科學家的溫床?
Human trials are a vital part of modern medicine.
臨床實驗是現代醫學的關鍵
Yeah,but don't people usually volunteer or sign waivers,maybe get some dough for tuition.
不是得自願 簽署個棄權書或者 是掙點學費嗎?
Sometimes you do what's necessary for the greater good.
為了完成更大的目標 一點犧牲是必須的
I'm not the greatest guy in the world,but it sounds like some Mengele level crap
我不是偉人 但你剛才說的跟 Mengele說的廢話一樣 (德國納粹醫生)
that you're spouting out,so I got to ask... What is your greater good?
所以想問下 什麼是更大的目標?
Rabies.Sounds fun,doesn't it,and appropriate given the circumstance.
狂犬病毒 刺激吧 而且很符合 現在的氣氛哦
Are you doing ok?
你還好嗎?
- Am I on the famous other side?- You are.
- 我是在所謂的另一邊嗎? - 是的
- What,um... What got you here?- I died.
- 你怎麼在這裡? - 我死了
- No.I mean,what were you?- A witch.
- 不 你是幹什麼的? - 女巫
What are you?
你呢?
The anchor to the other side.Every supernatural being who dies passes through me.
連接另外世界的錨 每一個 死去的超自然生物都會經過我
That doesn't seem like it'd be a lot of fun for you.
這對於你不是好事嘛
It's better than being dead.
比死好
I'm so sorry.Such a stupid thing to say.
對不起 說這話真該死
It's ok,honey.Dying wasn't fun,but then you felt my pain,so I guess you know that.
親愛的 沒事 死亡很痛苦 我經過你時 你會感受到
I'm sorry,but you know what?
真抱歉 但你知道嗎?
The pain's gone now,and seeing a friendly face over here certainly doesn't hurt.
痛苦消失了 看到這麼友善的面孔 感覺好了很多
Sorry!
對不起!
Pretty much had to wrestle Elena to get her to give me these.
這可是強迫Elena才得到的
- You ok?- Yeah.I think I am.
- 你沒事吧? - 沒事
Good.I'm gonna need you to come with me.
跟我來
Where are we going?
去哪?
To register for classes.
去"登記上課"
That feels amazing.
這樣感覺很棒
That's one of the other fun side effects.
變成吸血鬼後另一個變化
Everything is heightened.
每一種情感都會放大
So that feeling never goes away?
這感覺不會消失?
Nope.
不會
Well,rabies was a bust.
狂犬病毒太遜啦
I guess I'll find something a little more immediate.
我去找點立竿見影的
I wanted to turn Jesse into a new kind of vampire.
我是想把Jesse變成新型吸血鬼
Well,that's awfully ambitious of you.
野心不小啊
I am awfully smart.
我很聰明
Ebola.
埃博拉病毒
Why?
為什麼?
Your kind is dangerous to humans.
你們一直是人類的威脅
You're dangerous because we're your food source.I want to change that.
因為人類一直是盤中餐 我想改變這點
What?
怎麼了?
Last time I kissed you,you got all weird,and it was awkward,and...
上次吻你時 你反應有點奇怪 場景有點尷尬
If vampires don't need to feed on humans,they're no longer a threat.
如果吸血鬼不再以人血為食 就不會是人類的威脅
I'm not buying the good doctor bit.
我才不信你是啥好醫生
Human blood will only satiate Jesse temporarily until he gets a taste of what he really craves.
人類血液只能暫時滿足Jesse 他會知道自己真正需要什麼
Well,what exactly does he really crave?
他到底需要什麼?
You bit me.
你咬我
- Hey.You ok?- Yeah.I just got to get out of here.
- 你沒事吧? - 沒事 我走了
Jesse!
Jesse
Ok.So this isn't the lamest party that I've ever been to.
看來這不是我經歷過的最遜的派對
Aaron,hey.You made it.
Aaron 你來了
Barely.I think I fell asleep.I just woke up.
差點來不了 我好像睡著了 剛醒呢
Weird.Well,this will make it better.
好吧 這個會讓你感覺好點
Oh.Now I know why Wes told me to stay away from you.
知道為什麼Wes讓我遠離你了
Cheers.
乾杯
You're trouble.
你還真是麻煩
- So,hey.How do you know Wes anyway?- He's my legal guardian.
- 你怎麼認識Wes的? - 他是我的監護人
- Really?- Mm-hmm.
- 真的? - 恩
- What about your parents?- Uh,dead.
- 父母呢? - 死了
Mine,too.Birth and adoptive.
我也是 親生父母 養父母都死了
Whoa.Dark.No offense,but usually,I'm the biggest freak in the room.
噢 好灰暗 正常來說我是這個房間裡 最怪咖的
So how'd it happen?
怎麼回事?
Uh,our car went over a bridge.I lived,they didn't.You?
車翻到了橋下 我生還 他們沒有 你呢?
I was 6,and we went camping,and I woke up to the sound of my mom screaming.
六歲的時候去露營 我被母親的 尖叫聲驚醒
I went to check it out,and I saw blood everywhere.
我起來查看 到處是血
They had bite marks all over their neck.
他們的脖子上全是咬痕
Bite marks?
咬痕?
Yeah.They said a bear got into the camp.So I shuffled around distant relatives for a while.
是的 說是熊襲擊了他們 在遠方親戚當中 我輪流過了一陣
Eventually,Wes took me in.
最終Wes收留了我
So Wes is the closest thing to family I have left.
Wes是我最親近的家人
I think both need another jell-o shot.I'll be right back.I'm glad that you came.
咱還需要喝個果凍酒 馬上過來 很高興你能來
Yeah.Me,too.
我也是
- Hey.Have you seen Jesse?- No.
- 看到Jesse了嗎? - 沒有
Wait.Where are you going?
喂 你去哪?
To call Damon,to make sure that he doesn't kill Dr.Wes.
給Damon電話 讓他一定不要殺Wes博士
There you are.
你在這
Get away from me.
走開
Stefan,you're ok.Relax.
Stefan 你沒事的 放鬆
I can't do that.Do you understand me?
我做不到 明白嗎?
You have two options,Stefan.
Stefan你有兩個選擇
You either deal with this now,or you run,but either way,it's gonna catch up to you.
勇敢面對或者逃避 但記憶都會如影隨形
I can't breathe,Stefan.
Stefan我無法呼吸了
Tell me the name of the first person that you kill... killed.
你殺的第一個人叫什麼名字
Name him.
說他的名字
Gius... Giuseppe Salvatore.
Gius...Giuseppe Salvatore
And the next?
第二個
Focus on the name.
想名字
Thomas Fell.
Thomas Fell
See?You're in control,on solid ground.
看 你能控制自己 好好的呢
You're not drowning.You're not dying.
你沒有溺水 也不會死
Name them.
說出他們的名字
Honoria Fell,Marianna Lockwood,Christopher Gilbert,Margaret Forbes.
Honoria Fell Marianna Lockwood Christopher Gilbert Margaret Forbes
See?I told you I knew what I was doing.
看 我知道我在做什麼
Thank you.
謝謝你
You're right.Gregor is dead.Happy now?
你是對的 Gregor死了 你高興了吧
You deserve better,Nadia.
你值得更好的 Nadia
Rot in hell.
你下地獄吧
Jesse feeds on... Vampires?
Jesse吸吸血鬼的血嗎
That's what Doogie said,and apparently once he starts,he can't stop.
狗狗說的 很顯然 一旦開口 他就滔滔不絕
Hey.Um,the fact that he told you this means that he's still alive,right?
他這麼說 說明他還活著 對吧
As of now.
目前是這樣
Good.Please don't kill him,Damon.
好 不要殺他 Damon
Damon,tell me that you won't kill him.
Damon 保證你不會殺他
Ok,ok,ok.I won't kill him.Bye.
好好 我不會的 拜
Problem is I know people like you a lot better than you realize.
我比你想像的更瞭解你這種人
If I let you live,you're just gonna do it again.
如果你活著 你就會再犯
You're gonna turn another vampire,you're gonna do another experiment.
轉化新的吸血鬼做新實驗
The only way to really handle you is just to snuff you out.
唯一的方法就是殺了你
You're lucky I don't feel like burying a body.
你很幸運 我不想殺人
- What the hell did you do to me?- Easy there,killer.
- 你對我做了什麼 - 別緊張 殺手
Wasn't bad enough that you locked me up and poked me full of needles?
把我關起來用針扎我還不夠嗎
Now I want to feed on the girl I like?
我竟然還想喝我心愛女生的血?
You feed on monsters,Jesse.
你是想喝怪物的血 Jesse
In case Professor Forbes forgot to tell you in your training,sweetie,
親 如果Forbes教授在訓練你時 沒告訴你
I'm a lot older than you,and that means I'm a lot stronger than you.
我比你老自然比你強
Actually that's not 100% accurate.
不完全對
What the hell did they do to you?
他們對你做了什麼
Damon!
Damon
Jesse,Jesse,let go.Jesse!
Jesse Jesse 放開 Jesse
He's gonna tear my head off.Elena,please.
他要撕下我的頭 救我 Elena
No!No!No,Jesse!Jesse,come here.
不 Jesse 過來
Hold on.Hold on.Just stay with me,please.Jesse,just stay with me,please.No.
堅持住 別離開我 Jesse 求你了 不
- What did you do?- He was gonna kill Damon.
- 你做了什麼 - 他要殺Damon
But we promised that we would help him.
我們說過會幫他的
She didn't have a choice,all right?
她別無選擇
Once he had the taste of vampire blood,there was nothing stopping him.
他一旦嘗過吸血鬼的味道就停不下來了
Go ask Dr.Frankenstein.I'll go deal with him.
去問怪咖博士 我來解決他
- Caroline,I'm so sorry.I... - Yeah.Me,too.
- Caroline 我很抱歉 - 我也是
Because the Elena that I used to know would have given Jesse a chance.
我曾認識的Elena會給Jesse一個機會
Dear Nadia,sorry I had to kill your boyfriend,but it was the motherly thing to do.
親愛的Nadia 很抱歉殺了你的男朋友 但那是母性
Suicide,however,not very motherly of me.
自殺 也許不是母親該做的
I ran from my enemies for 500 years,and then one day,I stopped.
我已經逃了500年 終有一天我可以停下
Now a new enemy wants me dead.
現在又有人要我死
Sure I could run from the travelers,but there's still one enemy that I can never escape,time.
我可以繼續逃避旅行者 可我永遠逃不開...時間
So call it pride or vanity,but after the life that I've led,I refuse to drift off into the sunset.
驕傲也好虛榮也好 經過這一切 我不想衰老而死
Good-bye,Nadia.
再見了 Nadia
What are you doing?
你幹什麼
I told you you either face your problems,or you run.I chose option 3.
我曾告訴你面對或逃避 我選擇第三個
And what problem has you jumping off of a clock tower?
你為什麼從鐘樓跳下來
I'm dying,Stefan.I'm dying of old age.
我要死了 Stefen 死於年老
I don't know the cure did something to speed up the entire mortifying process.
我不知道解藥會加速衰老
Yeah.You're Katherine Pierce.Suck it up.
對 但你是Katherine Pierce 只能忍著
I'll admit it..I miss magic.
我得承認我想念魔法
Step away from the candles.
別管那些蠟燭了
Oh,my God.
天哪
I think Jesse's dead.
我看到Jesse死了
What?
什麼
I'm not ready.I don't want this.
我還沒準備好 我不想這樣
Bonnie,what's going on?Bonnie!
Bonnie 怎麼了Bonnie
What is it?
那是什麼
I'm the anchor to the other side,Jer.
我是通向另一個世界的錨 Jer
Every supernatural being that dies has to pass through me.
每個超自然的生命死去都要通過我
How often does that happen?Why... why didn't you tell me?
多久一次 為什麼不告訴我
I'm back here,touching you.We knew there would be consequences.
我回到這 可以觸摸你 我們都知道回來是有代價的
Just kiss me.Kiss me.
吻我
You... and me... This,this is worth it.Any consequence is worth this.
你我是值得的 任何代價都值得
I'm sorry.I didn't mean what I said earlier.It was out of line.
很抱歉 我不是那個意思 我過分了
It just sucks,you know,cause Jesse was one of the good ones.
只是很糟 Jesse是個好人
I know,and I wouldn't have killed him if I could have done something.
如果我能做什麼我不會殺他的
He was dangerous.I need you to believe that.I need you to believe me when I tell you that Caroline.
他太危險了 你要相信我 Caroline
I believe you,ok?
好 我相信你
I believe you want to celebrate the fact that we can go to school and function like regular freshmen.
我相信你想慶祝一下 我們能像正常新生一樣上學
I get that.I want that,too,but,Elena,when are you gonna figure out that
我懂 我也想 可Elena你什麼時候才能明白
the outside world is not nearly as dangerous as the person you're inviting into your own bedroom?
外面的世界還沒有你的枕邊人危險呢
Why don't you tell me how you really feel?
為什麼不告訴我你的感覺
The day that I stop telling you is the day that we're no longer best friends,and...
當我們不再是死黨了 我就不告訴你了
I hope that day never comes.
希望那天永遠不來
If you're gonna do this,I'd much rather prefer a bullet through the brain.
如果你這麼做我寧願自殺
Actually I'm gonna wait until I can compel all this out of your head.
我會等到 可以蠱惑你忘掉這一切
What the hell's that?
那是什麼
Why does this say 12144?
這寫著12144是啥意思?
What do you care?
你關心個什麼勁?
Because I was 21051.
我是21051
21051.Hang on.You were an Augustine vampire?
21051 等會 你是Augustine吸血鬼
Augustine.I haven't heard that name in decades.
Augustine 很久沒聽過了
Vampire lab rats,coded subject names.I thought you guys shut down 60 years ago.
吸血鬼小白鼠 編碼名字 我以為你們60年前都結束了
You thought wrong.
你錯了
You know how I said I wasn't gonna kill you?I lied.
我說不會殺你 我撒謊了
Atomized vervain.When working with vampires,you can never be too careful.
霧化馬鞭草 跟吸血鬼工作一定要小心
I'm sure Augustine will be thrilled to have you back.
Augustine會很高興你回去的
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=-Proudly Presents
-------------------------------------- 本論壇字幕僅翻譯交流學習之用 禁止任何商業用途否則後果自負 --------------------------------------
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com/bbs=-Sync: YTET-橙子
-=YTET-伊甸園字幕組=- 翻譯: Noodles 兜兜 絮兒 小蟲cherry 校對: 艾瑞瑞 時間軸: 橙子
The vampire diaries Season5Episode 8
吸血鬼日記 第五季 第8集 完